[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
tricentis tasar automation tutorial as
you all know I've already published 60
YouTube videos covering beginners level
intermediate level and advanced level
Concepts from few days onwards have
started teaching you the realtime
scenarios where you might encounter
different types of obstacles and how can
we solve those obstacles while
automating your test cases by using
tricentis tasar tricentis tasar please
do subscribe to the channel click on
Bell icon you'll receive notifications
whenever I publish more videos don't
forget to like and share the video thank
you
this is our lesson 61 in terms of
overall tricentis tosa automation
tutorial and this is our lesson 19 or
obstacle 19 in terms of realtime
scenarios in this lesson I'm going to
teach you how can we solve an
obstacle where you need to interact with
a dynamic web table to get last table
row value or to get last content Row
from the dynamic web table and enter the
last table row value into an edit box
now let us go to obstacle list and try
to understand in detail what is the
obstacle that we need to solve so this
is our obstacle which is named as the
last row and which is categorized as
medium so let us go for
it in order to complete this obstacle
you need to verify that the last row in
the table displays an order value and
then take this value and put it into
text field so what is the last row order
value our last row order value is
6124 pound so let me enter
6124 into this particular box
as soon as you enter including the pound
symbol it says you you solv this
problem you solve this automation
problem which means and one more thing
is this particular table is a dynamic
table so as soon as I refesh as soon as
I refresh now I can see a table with
less rows correct So This Time Again 8
3.9 pound symbol see done if I refresh
it again your table changes see now your
number of rows in the table got changed
and the value also changed so how can we
automate this particular test case to
capture
the value from the last
row of the table and enter the same in
this particular edit box so for that let
us go to PR
to as usual we are capturing all the
modules in folder called obstacles right
let's double click on this obstacles
folder and these are the obstacles that
we are capturing right these are all the
obstacles till
date I have posted in the YouTube now
right right click on this particular
obstacle click on scan
select
application now this is the application
which I love to which I would like to
automate select
scan so here now what are the objects
that that I
require what are the object objects that
I require to capture one is this order
table and this edit box right so here is
my order table select
this and this is my edit box order value
where I'm entering the value from the
last row of your
table select this one as
two done now let us name now let us
rename this module
with the name of your obstacle copy this
name and
then paste it
here and now let's save the
module and close your
xcan go back to your trient tasa and
verify the module that we captured so
this is the module right obstruct 703 31
0 double click on this so I can see here
Order table order value now let us
automate this particular scenario to do
so go to your left section which is a
blue section test case section okay so
this is the obstacle folder or test case
folder where we are capturing or this is
our test case folder where we are
automating each and every obstacle okay
right click on this and select create
new test case and name this test case
with the same obstacle name right and
double click on this so now to automate
your test case I'm going to drag and
drop this module that we captured just
now drag this and drop onto your test
case and now to automate the test case
there are two
methods okay so I'm going to go with the
first method my first method is so you
can see here Order table contains two
different modules which is row and
column right so this table has row and
column now if I go to
row I can see lot of values here if I
expand this drop
down dollar 1 dollar n dollar lost
dollar header dollar first empty row
dollar lost content row dollar one means
it's my first row dollar N means if you
want to specify it as a three four right
if you specify four that means you are
fourth row and then dollar last means
it's a last okay so however what we are
going to do here now to get the value
from the last row of the table I'm going
to start using
last this is my
last row
right I'm instructing it as a last row
as soon as you select last row now it
will ask you to select the cell is it
cell from your type or the cell of value
that means column of type or column of
value it's going to show your columns
here see here type value
I know which is a last row but when you
select last but when you select last row
what is your column or what is the cell
that you would like to capture the value
my cell is under value column right so
that's why I'm going to select
value now instead of verifying the value
I'm not I don't want to verify this one
instead I want to capture this value
into a buffer so hence what I'm going to
do here I'm going to
select a buffer value okay last row
value this is my buffer okay I would
like to store the value from this cell
into a buffer called last row value and
hence my action mode should not be
verified my action mode should be buffer
okay done now I'm storing the value of
last row from the cell into your buffer
right and
now the value I need to print in the
edit
box but that here under order Val order
value edit box I would like to print the
value from this buffer I would like to
call this buffer here
what is it what how can we call the
buffer open curly braces anytime any
method you want to use in
Tria you have to use open curly braces
capital B is for buffer and open Square
braces this is your
last
row value this is my buffer name close
quare braces and then close curly bra
right and your action mode input because
I would like to enter the value of this
buffer okay so now what I'm going to do
here let's save the test case and let me
run this test case when I run this test
case your order value should be entered
as 6431 pound let's run this right click
and run in scratchbook
see 6 4 3 1 pound you can see here you
solve this automation problem
successfully if I escape this see 6431
pound that's why our test case is
successful so now let us go back to your
test results you can see here now you
have
stored last row value here let me see
I'm storing the last row value under
buffer last row value what is the value
6431 the same thing that we entered here
okay now what is the second method so
what I'm going to do I'm going to drag
and drop this module one more time onto
the same test case okay so here what I'm
going to do I'm going to name this as
method
two okay so here again same we are going
to do the only change is here under row
last time what we selected we selected
last row so instead of selecting last
row I'm going to select last content
row okay I'm selecting last content row
as soon as you select last content Row
Your Action mode should be select only
okay and here in the cell I'm going to
select value right I need the value from
the column value I'm selecting the same
right and here instead of verify I would
like to mention it as buffer and here
what is my buffer name I would like to
select the buffer name as last row
content last row
content and once you store the value
into this buffer now I need to enter
here right what I'm going to do here let
me
read so what I'm going to do here under
order value I'm going to call this
buffer open curly braces capital B
last
[Music]
row content close curly braces sorry
close Square braces close curly bra your
action mode should be input so what is
the difference the only difference is
here I'm using
the I'm using the row index as dollar
lost but here in the second method I'm
using the row index as dollar lost
content row and rest all same now I'm
going to change the work state as
completed save this so let me run this
my second method okay let me run the
second method right click and run in
scratchbook see now it entered the value
correctly whatever the last row value it
has taken and it entered the same so
that means our test case is successful
here again your last row content value
what is that your last row content value
is 60
4 pound so let's go here you can see 604
pound right so that means the last row
content index also working correctly so
these are the two methods you can
automate your test Case by interacting
with
Dynamic web table and you can capture
the value of your last row so if you
have any queries leave your queries in
the comment box I'll try to respond to
your
queries oh you all understand how can we
solve an obstacle where you need to
interact with Dynamic web table to get
last row value or to get last content
row please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos don't forget to like and share
the video thank you
[Music]